# Ryan Compton

### Senior Data Scientist

San Francisco, California, United States ryancompton.james@gmail.com Website: https://rcompt.github.io/ LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ryanjamescompton

Github: github.com/rcompt

I am a Data Scientist/Researcher exploring how to bridge the insights gained from machine learning systems into fair, accountable, and transparent models. I currently work at Climate LLC as a Senior Data Scientist where I build AI systems with actionable insights for farmers.

# **Professional Experience**

Senior Data Scientist Climate LLC, San Francisco, California, United States | January 2022 - Present

- Developed deep learning models to support farming management practices.
- Built MLOps processes for robust statistical and machine learning models in production.
- Mentored interns working on experimental deep learning projects enhancing modeling capabitlies using transformer layers.
- Lead coding and software engineering cultural principles within the modeling organization.

Senior Data Scientist C3.ai, Redwood City, California, United States | March 2020 - December 2021

- Implemented large scale AI production systems with actionable insights across medical, financial, and manufacturing industries.
- Contributed to internal product development of C3's AI platform for automated model governance.
- Lead research on state-of-the-art approaches for Explainable AI and Graphical Applications.

Data Scientist Quantiply Corporation, San Jose, California | May 2019 - November 2019

- Built explainable AI systems to combat money laundering.
- Conducted research on Dynamic Clustering, Graph Embeddings, and Explainable Al insights.
- Lead and expanded Data Science team.

# **Key Skills**

- Machine Learning | Deep Learning (PyTorch, Tensorflow), Natural Language Processing, Graphical and Causal Modeling, Reinforcement Learning
- Solutions Architecture and Software Eng. | Scalability, Performance Optimization, Requirements Gathering, Data Pipelining, Governance
- Quantitative/Qualitative Research Methods | Experimental Design, User Experience Research, A/B Testing, Surveys
- Programming | Python, Java, Javascript, C#, C

# Projects/Publications

## Risks and Remedies for Black Box Artificial Intelligence

A discussion on advantages and implementing interpretable AI. https://c3.ai/blog/risks-and-remedies-for-black-box-artificial-intelligence/

#### Vec2Struc: A Method Towards Explainable Structural-Based Node Embeddings

Publication on a method providing a means to explore embeddings distributionally and visually. https://ceur-ws.org/Vol-2600/short2.pdf

#### User Experience and Prototyping with Progressive Web Apps

Exploration of UX considerations when building a Progressive Web App. https://medium.com/ebaydesign/manifest-destiny-92cdace24869

#### Education

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD) in Computer Science University of California, Santa Cruz | 2013 - 2019

Bachelor of Science (BS) in Psychology and Computer Science University of Arizona | 2007 - 2013